Junyoung Park

Website: pjywang.github.io Email: junyoup@umich.edu

Research Interests

I am broadly interested in data analysis that involves unique geometric structures necessitating rigorous treatment. My recent research focuses on distributional data analysis for applications to wearable device data. In addition, I have an interest in compositional data analysis for microbiome data and various dimension reduction methods.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Mathematical Sciences

03/2018 - 02/2024

KAIST, Daejeon, Korea

Thesis: Kernel Methods for Compositional Data and Dimensionality Reduction

(Co)Advisors: Cheolwoo Park, Jeongyoun Ahn

B.S. in Mathematics

03/2013 - 02/2018

Korea University, Seoul, Korea

Professional Positions

Postdoctoral Research Fellow

09/2024 -

Department of Biostatistics, University of Michigan, MI, USA

Supervisor: Irina Gaynanova

BK21 Postdoctoral Research Fellow

03/2024 - 08/2024

Natural Science Research Institute, KAIST, Daejeon, Korea

Supervisor: Cheolwoo Park

Funded by the BK21 project in Korea

EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant in Statistical Learning

KAIST

Under the supervision of Prof. Cheolwoo Park and Jeongyoun Ahn

08/2021 - 02/2024

- Kernel methods, compositional data, dimension reduction, autoencoder clustering

Technical Research Personnel

KAIST

For military duty in South Korea

03/2020 - 02/2023

Research Assistant in Algebraic Geometry

KAIST

Under the supervision of Prof. Sijong Kwak

09/2018 - 07/2021

- Projective geometry, syzygies, applied algebraic geometry
- Extensive training in geometry, algebra, and analysis at the graduate level and beyond

University Financial Engineering Association (U.FE.A)

Seoul, Korea

Team leader

03/2016 - 08/2017

- Led Master's-level financial engineering & mathematics studies
- Stochastic modeling and hedge (pricing) theory of various equity, interest rate derivatives

AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

- Presentation Award for Graduate Students, 2nd place, Korean Statistical Society (KSS) 2022
- The Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award, Calculus II, KAIST

Fall, 2020

- University Students Contest of Mathematics, Silver Awards, Korean Mathematical Society (KMS) 2016, 2017
- Presidential Science Undergraduate Fellowship, fully funded for 8 semesters

2013 - 2018

• The Korean Mathematical Olympiad (KMO) 2nd round of middle school division, Gold Awards 2009

Publications

- Park, J., Ahn, J., and Park, C. (2023), Kernel Sufficient Dimension Reduction and Variable Selection for Compositional Data via Amalgamation, In *International Conference on Machine Learning* (ICML), pp. 27034-27047, PMLR (link).
- 2. Kang, I., Choi, H., Yoon, Y.-J., **Park, J.**, Kwon, S.-S., and Park, C. (2023), Frechet Distance-Based Cluster Analysis for Multi-Dimensional Functional Data, *Statistics and Computing*, 33(4), 75.
- 3. Park, J., Yoon, C., Park, C., and Ahn, J. (2022), Kernel Methods for Radial Transformed Compositional Data with Many Zeros, In *International Conference on Machine Learning* (ICML), pp. 17458-17472, PMLR (link).

In progress:

1. Interpretable Dimension Reduction for Compositional Data (with Jeongyoun Ahn and Cheolwoo Park), partially appeared in my Ph.D. dissertation.

Talks

• 2024 Joint Statistical Meetings

08/2024

Oregon Convention Center, Portland, OR, USA

- Title: Interpretable dimension reduction for compositional data
- 2023 Winter Conference, the Korean Statistical Society Sungshin Women's University, Seoul, Korea

12/2023

- Title: Interpretable composition-to-composition dimension reduction via conditional covariance operator
- 40th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) (postered)
 Honolulu, HI, USA

07/2023

- Title: Kernel sufficient dimension reduction and variable selection for compositional data via Amalgamation
- $\bullet\,$ 2023 Summer Conference, the Korean Statistical Society

06/2023

- Pukyong National University, Busan, Korea
- Title: Kernel sufficient dimension reduction and variable selection for compositional data via Amalgamation
- 2022 Fall KAIST Math Graduate student Seminar

10/2022

- KAIST, Daejeon, Korea
- Title: Kernel methods for radial transformed compositional data with many zeros
- 39th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) (spolight talk) Baltimore, MD, USA

06/2022

- Title: Kernel methods for radial transformed compositional data with many zeros
- Presented also at 2022 Summer Conference, the Korean Statistical Society, Seoul (awarded, 2nd place)

Teaching

- Statistical Data Science Practice (DS516)	Spring 2023
- Probability and Statistics (MAS250)	Fall 2021
- Abstract Algebra I (MAS311)	Spring 2021
- Mathematical Statistics (MAS355)	Fall 2019
- Matrix Group Theory (MAS435)	Spring 2019
Cave a guest leature on connectedness of Lie groups in English	

· Gave a guest lecture on connectedness of Lie groups in English

- Abstract Algebra II (MAS312) Fall 2018

· Gave several lectures throughout the semester

Academic Services

• Journal Refereeing

- Biometrics
- WIREs Computational Statistics

Computing Skills

- Python (for machine learning, statistics), R (for statistics), previous experiences with Matlab and C
- Acceleration of optimization: experience in leveraging TensorFlow AutoGraph in my research
- Familiar with Linux environment for high-performance computing systems
- Parallel programming in R and Python

LANGUAGES

- Korean (native)
- English

Hobbies

- Singing, better with playing guitar.
- Running, hiking, and climbing.

REFERENCES

Cheolwoo Park

Department of Mathematical Sciences and Graduate School of Data Science KAIST

parkcw2021@kaist.ac.kr

Jeongyoun Ahn

Department of Industrial & Systems Engineering and Graduate School of Data Science KAIST

jyahn@kaist.ac.kr

Sijong Kwak (former advisor in mathematics)

Department of Mathematical Sciences KAIST

sjkwak@kaist.ac.kr